I had a friend over for coffee yesterday
and one of the things I told her the
story of my neighbor and how she came
over and wouldn't leave despite being
told to leave that we're not having this
conversation right now
and couldn't close the door couldn't end
the conversation the interaction part of
what came out of that conversation with
my friend is this realization that the
funny thing was that is what happens
with the neighbor it was like a forced
conversation that in no way was like a
good conversation because it was forced
right it like one party was like no this
isn't happening right now the other one
was like you're gonna listen this is
gonna happen right now in my way and the
violence is from the force because I'm
here to have conversations the difficult
ones all of them the uncomfortable ones
but I get to choose whatever part of
them everyone gets to choose when
they're a part of them and the beauty
that comes from being part of a chosen
conversation where people feel safe and
heard and we can have the difficult
conversations but only people who need
to have those conversations and want to
have those conversations have to
participate for seeing people to have
difficult conversations is not okay not
listening to people's clear signals of
like this conversation isn't happening
right now
I have adrenaline running through my
body it's not safe I need to go and not
be part of this conversation just that
that that realization that like it's the
voluntary peace that went from it being
like a really bad interaction to be in a
really positive interaction my
interactions like my whole life is
revolving around a conversation having a
conversation one way on YouTube having
lots of conversations that are 2-way on
video chat or more than two way in
groups and thriving from that like
people who are who are choosing to be
part of those conversations choosing to
interact in a way and when things
fall apart even a little bit owning it
making amends figuring out how to move
forward together and that's an
individual right like where did I go
wrong how do I apologize for it how do i
how do I fix it and that's to me the big
difference like this this um capitalism
versus communism debate that um you know
we can't we can't get rid of capitalism
this communism is the alternative and to
me
capitalism is forced competition it's
not it's like you compete or you starve
and communism is forced cooperation it's
do what's better for the group or he
starve or you could you know get
imprisoned and so it's not competition
versus cooperation it's forced
competition versus forced cooperation
and I think both of those things when
done voluntarily have a much better
impact if you can voluntarily choose
wearing your life you're competing so
that you're getting the biggest benefit
as an individual right like never we
outline sports any competition and if it
helps you thrive we should have it but
for some people who don't thrive in
competition to have to compete is unkind
and violent
similarly for scene people who don't
want to be in cooperation who don't want
to do what's in it for the greater good
who don't want to work unless someone's
working more right who don't want to to
produce the most be the most that they
want to be because they see it as like
it's forced they don't want to do it
because it's forced whereas when you can
tap into the voluntary nature of both of
those things and you can choose as the
individual how much competitions in your
life and how much cooperation and see
the benefits of cooperation and
competition and like truly see the
benefits and get the benefits back then
you're I believe you'll choose
cooperation more often but not everybody
will competition is still a important
aspect of our society the people thrive
under but forced competition not okay
forced cooperation equally if not more
Island in history and so having
voluntary cooperation where everything
is an attractor if it can be done better
with competition it's going to be done
better with competition and it can be
done better with cooperation it's going
to be done better with cooperation and
in that in that realm
I believe cooperation of competes
competition a cooperative a ball and
Terry cooperative that you can come and
get your needs met and he'll be heard
and help improve it out competes
competition that is like we're in it for
ourselves the biggest firm wins the you
know and then you get richer and richer
and richer because this has one winner
and this has everyone winning but
outline this hurts this and forcing this
hurts this so it's the voluntary piece
that we are tapping into and that came
up about my purpose right now is to have
conversations and the one that was
forced on me
was the the violent one the one that is
not welcome in my life or community and
it was the forced piece that was the
problem